Ok. Uh Hello, Ivan.
So I have been working on this project, uh Hospital Bank uh for the last few days.
So let's start the demo of this project
before, but before getting into demo, um I would like to discuss that.
W what was the problem statement that I chose for this project?
Ok. So when uh we live with a roommate or, you know, in hostel,
normally what happens? We lend our friend some money
and uh after that, it's really hard to keep track of like how much we uh
give, how much we have to take
and all that stuff.
OK. So for that, there are various application available uh out there.
So I thought, why not we create our own application for this? OK.
So that's why I created this.
Uh So let's start.
OK. So first, uh let's uh sign in
uh will I will use this account?
Ok. So for
signing, I have used basic logic that I have,
uh I uh we just pass the email and the password.
Then I have also used
decrypt for
loading the password,
um you know, for the security of the user data
so that even if data was compromises, the password remains secure.
Ok.
So let's sign in.
So once you sign in, we will uh
get into this, the home page.
And yeah, along with the signing for
signing for authentication and for authorization, I have used JW
token.
So that user uh don't need to, uh, sign in again and again,
if uh they close the tab right now, for example, if I close this tab right now
and I just
uh uh
you know, uh went to the same homepage, same website.
So let's say uh
OK.
Yeah, so I automatically get signed into the
account, right?
Why? Because I have to wear the,
you know, uh the token, uh a
local student
will automatically get uh used for signing.
OK.
So, OK, let's,
let's just see how this token actually is transmitted to backend uh as soon as we,
you know, uh enter this page.
OK.
So if we just uh
go to the networks
and let's say I go to this group P A
request is sent to the back end to get the group info
right now. This user has not any uh not joined any groups. So it's empty.
So if I go on this request and uh look here for something as token. Yeah. So token,
you will see this screen. So this is nothing but AJ W token
which helps to authorize this user. OK?
And if we go,
uh you know, on uh let's say a
WT dot A
U,
we can also see what exactly this uh
a token is saying or sending to the back
that
it here
you will see here
what exactly
uh is the content of this thing.
So yeah, we know we cannot read it directly,
we can see it, but actually, we cannot authorize it uh or check it when
five is true or not. That can be done only using the key uh which is present on the back.
OK. So yeah, so that was about arthritis. And, and
I
thank the
uh so let's continue.
Uh So let's, let's create a group
uh inside our application.
So let's, we will go to the create a group tab
and here we will, let's say, create a group names, let's say
uh
OK.
And create.
So as soon as we click on, create groups,
uh a group is created and we,
we get uh a code to join that group so we can share this code uh with whomever you want uh
to be a part of that group. OK.
So I'll copy this one. OK.
Now the code is copy. And if I go to groups
here, I will see the uh list of the group that I have joined
right now. If we try to enter this group,
uh we will see there is only one member
because no one else is present in this book. OK?
So let's do one thing I will use another account to join this group. OK.
So yeah, so I have already signed in
um
to another account
uh in another tab. OK. Let's go to join groups
and I will paste that group code
here and join group.
OK? So after some time, I will get a message
that I have joined the group
and here. So I have joined host
group successfully.
So if I go to groups
then yeah. So here you will see the hospital group
and if I go in that group,
you will see the both
accounts,
the account, our account, my account, the current
that is this Don
at gmail
and the other uh
individuals that have, that have written in this book.
So let's do one thing.
Uh let's create a request of let's say ₹10
for, let's say a good week.
Ok.
And send a request.
So as soon as I send the request,
uh we'll get a pop up saying the request has done successfully
and you can see here uh a ₹10
amount has been added in the section of to
take.
OK.
Now, uh if we go to email of uh this person, we will see we will get a notification,
right?
So yeah, so we hello, we have got a notification
of type request
and if we again go to that person's account,
we have to just to refresh this. So we will uh
OK, just OK, this is the issue of uh
because it doesn't allow
direct jumping from the end point.
So we just have to
go to home page.
Yeah.
Ok.
So yeah, so when I will Yeah, so
get notifications
if we see you, I will get a request of ₹10 and notice will pay.
Now let's say
I will say, ok, I have got a request now let's say
I want to pay this and I paid it using my le lets A GP
you know what I will do.
I will go to groups in that group. I will enter that group
and click on
set up.
Once I settle this,
uh I will be if you would ask us
a G
if you want to settle it.
And yes, so we'll see that. Ok?
And the amount here will become zero.
Now,
if I go to the f
of this
account,
you will see that
uh there is an uh a notification that you have sent ₹10
to this particular account. On this day, we
will keep track of when we send how much rupees to one person.
And if we again go back to the
other account,
you will see
a notification that you have received 10
₹10
on this date from this account.
And in the history tab
as
well, you will see you have ₹15.
So
all the history is maintained here.
Additionally, you will receive an email every time uh his
order notifications arrived. Ok?
So you will you can keep track of everything that the transaction that you have made,
the request that you have received.
So it will become easy to calculate all that stuff at the end of the month. OK.
So now this is where the notification feature,
uh the group's feature
where you can see all the groups create group feature
where you can create the group join group feature,
where you can join the group if you have an ID
history feature,
uh where you will see all the money that you have spent and received
and I then this setting.
So in this setting, uh I have given us a feature to change your password.
So the logic for this is that when you uh enter your old password
and the new password that you want to uh set out your uh
password
and just check uh with the,
the data
that is this password
and the
password that current database have is same.
And if it just updates uh
to the new password, ok,
then additional features that I have provided is uh when,
when you forget your passport.
So for that, let's sign up.
OK.
So when you sign up, there is an option of forget, forgot password.
When you click here, uh
you just have to interview with email.
And if you,
you with email,
you will get a
uh a pass uh uh an email which will have a du a dummy password, a temporary password.
Uh that you can use to log in after that, you can uh change it.
OK?
So this was about the application
now about
the interesting part about the deployment.
So I have deployed both this application,
the, the applications on,
you know, a
ver version
platform
and as well as on aws. OK. So this one that I was using, so this one
is AWS dash
by,
uh I was able to log in uh with two different accounts in same tab. Uh,
otherwise, uh, you won't be able to do that
because basically like there are two different websites.
So, yeah,
so, uh on personal, it was pretty simple
but while deploying on Aws, I have tried to deploy it using wages services like uh
next day. Uh
ok, so this, this is a database that I have been using
uh to storing the data and all the transactions.
Yeah. And one more, one more interesting thing
that uh for storing a transaction of a group. I have used mattress,
I have, I have, uh used mattresses that
because I wanted to add one more feature that I'm working on,
which is, uh, you know, like auto
depth normalization means what let's say there are, uh, let's say, uh, in the group,
there are use that ABC.
If a, give a ₹10 to BB, gave ₹10 C
and C give ₹10 to A, then, you know,
we can normalize it like no one has to give
any amount back to anyone because they are settled.
So this was something that I am planning to implement.
And I think uh
by storing the transaction of a group in a matrix,
it can be acute.
So that's why I have stored it in the mattress. Ok.
So for the deployment,
so yes, this is my
Aws Council Council
and uh
I have deployed the backend on Aws
app runner.
Uh
Yeah. So
this is the deployment of the back end.
And for the front end,
I have used aws amplifier
and I have done another deployment just for exploring purpose that I tried to
use github actions.
Uh
uh What do I mean by uh bit of action is that I directly use, you know,
created ac two instance on Aws.
Uh
Let me show you that
uh
a very
OK.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
so what I did here was I already created a E two instance
uh then use the github
action. Uh This is the runner part uh runner that they provide
uh which uh helps
us to directly deploy uh my changes in the code uh in
the institute instance in that institute instance, I use Docker.
So basically, I didn't actually
uh directly created the environment inside the instant rather than I uh what I did,
I use the
Docker images uh
to do not to uh I important
Docker images on that
particular instrument.
Then uh then that landed a Docker images for the
front and backend separately and both of them are communicated.
So that was the logic that I used. Uh
So for that the,
the Docker
plot I created uh was this one?
So, yeah, so
for
that, you know, this is the basic Docker file
where I have
depend on the requirements and the a step that I have to take.
And uh
for, you know, for deployment purpose for C I CD,
I use this uh yeah, wireless file
where this was divided into two parts.
The first part was two building uh where I just uh
uh you know, I
put that image from the docket
and then build it and deploy it on that particular instance.
So yeah, so this was the part regarding the deployment
that I explored like using three services ac two instances
uh
where I used Docker,
uh I use Docker
up to
import I, I put it from the images from the dock it up
and let me show
you that images. Yeah.
So these were the
images that I was importing
there.
Then uh the prior that I showed was using uh app runner and the amplifier
app runner for the
los part for the back end uh
express server. And uh for react, I used uh the amplifier
service.
So yeah, this was a basic production.
And how are you
uh the project? Yeah. Additionally, for the notification part,
I have used the
uh note mailer along with Bravo
uh which provides you the service to send emails to the,
you know, your users. Uh It's a free API
uh So it has limited number of messages that you can send, but it's free.
Yeah.
So I also tried that. So
basically it was uh
or
it was a very good, great project.
I got to explore various things.
Yeah. So do try it out.
I will provide both the links uh the one of that,
uh, the
blood
person
and the other of the Aws. But mostly I will,
uh, pause the,
one of, uh, the Aws link, uh, because, yeah, it's a free
account
and I don't want to finish all my grades. So, yeah, so
do try it out
and see you in the next. Thank you.